Zichun (Frank) Zhao

McMaster University
Department of Economics
Kenneth Taylor Hall, Room 705
1280 Main Street West
Hamilton, Ontario
Canada L8S 4M4

University Profile: Zichun Zhao Email: zhaoz137@mcmaster.ca Website: zichunzhao.github.io LinkedIn: Zichun Zhao

PERSOANL PROFILE

Self-motivated and committed Ph.D. candidate in Health Economics from University of McMaster. Research focuses on evaluating healthcare policy and public policy on healthcare access. Four-year experience using advanced econometric models to analyze large administrative and survey datasets, such as DAD, NACRS, CCR, T1FF, CCHS and SHS. Strong communication and presentation skills. Adaptable team player with ability to work independently and meet the deadline.

EDUCATION

Ph.D. in Economics (Health Economics Specialization)

Sept. 2019 – Feb. 2024 (Expected)

McMaster University, Canada; GPA: 3.6/4.0

• Thesis Topic: Three Essays in Health Economics, Health Insurance and Public Policy

M.A. in Economics Sept. 2017 – May. 2019

University of Windsor, Canada; GPA: 3.9/4.0 (Top 1 in the Department)

- Major Paper: Economic Effects of Solar Activity: Evidence from Canada
- Certificate of Academic Achievement (\$800)

B.A. in Economics (Graduate with Distinction)

HeFei University of Technology (HFUT), China; GPA: 3.35/4.0

Sept. 2013 – May. 2017

PUBLICATIONS

- Z, Zhao, M, Grignon. "Cancer, Financial Burden and Health Insurance" (2023 In progress).
- Z, Zhao, M, Grignon. "The Spillover Effects of Public Prescription Drug Insurance Expansions on Emergency Department Usage: Evidence from Canada" (2022 In progress).
- Z, Zhao, M, Grignon. "The Effects of the Hiking Minimum Wages on Employer-Sponsored Supplementary Health Insurance in Canada" (2021 Under review Canadian Journal of Economics).
- M, Batu, Z, Zhao. "The Sun's Wrath: Economic Effects of Sunspot Volatility." Economics Bulletin 41, no. 1 (2021): 117-124.

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Research Assistant

McMaster University, Sept. 2022 – Apr. 2023

- Project: Child Penalty for Immigrant Women.
- Searched more than 1000 papers and materials from EconLit database about the causal effects of parenthood on women relative to men, outcomes include income, mental health and productivity.
- Wrote comprehensive and systematic literature reviews.
- Checked data quality, merged and linked various administrative datasets, including the DAD, NACRS, Longitudinal Immigration Database, and T1FF.

- Cleaned data such as winsorized extreme values and deleted duplicated observations.
- Conducted dynamic treatment effects models to estimate different effects of parenthood on incomes between fathers and mothers.
- Developed Stata and R code and created packages to duplicate research process.
- Prepared reports and slides and presented the results to supervisors.
- Received feedbacks from supervisors and other professors to revise the research methodology.

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Sessional Faculty

McMaster University, Sept. 2023 – Dec. 2023

- ECON 3C03: Public Economics: Taxation
- Stayed updated with recent trends in economics to enhance the course content, especially about the relationship between COVID-19 and public policy.
- Developed slides, assignments and formulated exam questions.
- Held regular office hours to address students' inquiries and gather feedbacks.

Teaching Assistant

McMaster University, Sept. 2019 - Present

- Prepared tutorials for econometric exercise using STATA and R.
- Assisted students in implementing data cleaning and regression analysis.
- Held office hours to provide personalized educational support.
- Invigilated and graded exams and reported the results to instructor.

CONFERENCE PRESENTATIONS

June. 2023	Presentation and Session Chair, Canadian Economics Association (Winnipeg, MAN)
June. 2022	Presentation and Session Chair, Canadian Economics Association (Ottawa, ON)
June. 2021	Presentation, New Frontier of Health Policy (McMaster, ON)
June. 2019	Presentation, Canadian Economics Association (Banff, AB)

SKILLS & LANGUAGES

Software & Programming: Stata, R, Tableau, LaTex, MS PowerPoint, Excel, Word

Languages: Fluent in English and Mandarin

REFERENCES

Dr. Michel Grignon, Professor

Department of Economics | Department of Health Aging & Society

McMaster University 1280 Main Street West Hamilton, ON, L8S 4L8

Kenneth Taylor Hall (KTH), Room 232 Phone: 905-525-9140, ext. 23493 Email: grignon@mcmaster.ca Dr. Katherine Cuff, Professor
Department of Economics
McMaster University
1280 Main Street West
Hamilton, ON, L8S 4L8
Kenneth Taylor Hall (KTH), Room 411
Phone: 905-525-9140, ext. 23827

Phone: 905-525-9140, ext. 23827 Email: cuffk@mcmaster.ca

Dr. Jonathan Zhang, Assistant Professor Department of Economics McMaster University 1280 Main Street West Hamilton, ON, L8S 4L8 Kenneth Taylor Hall (KTH), Room 421 Email: jonathanzhang@mcmaster.ca